(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T10:10:28.587008",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
しゅっ！
Shh!
さあ、始まりました！
Now then, it has begun!
白上フブキのすこんなばらえでぃ！
Shirakami Fubuki's Sukonna Variety!
皆さん、えーい！
Everyone, yay!
コメント欄がヤ号で溢れ返っている、一体誰が本物のヤ号なんだー！？
The chat is overflowing with Yagoos!
Who on earth is the real Yagoo!?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
さてさて、本日10月5日は白上の誕生日！ 皆さん本当にお祝いありがとうございます！
Now then, today, October 5th, is Shirakami's birthday!
Thank you all so much for the celebration!
コメントも見えとるぞ！
I can see the comments too!
こんなど真ん中のステージちょっと一人ぼっち寂しいですけども、 今回ですね全編通してはバラエティ企画となっております！
It's a bit lonely being all alone on this center stage,
but this time, the whole thing will be a variety special!
ハッシュタグはこちら #すこんなバラエティ でよろしくお願いします！ ヤ号がトレンドに入ったんだからこれもトレンド入りしますよね！？
Please use the hashtag #SukonnaVariety!
Since Yagoo trended, this should trend too, right!?
しますよね！？してくださーい！よろしくお願いします！
Right!? Please make it happen! I'm counting on you!
さて、えー実は白上前が見えてないんですよね。ちょっとサングラスもいつまでもこんなかけてられないんでちょっと外します。
Now, um, actually I can't really see in front of me.
Since I can't wear sunglasses forever, I'll take them off.
オッケーです！ちょっとファンの方に投げときました。
Okay! I just tossed them to the fans.
さてさてさて！ではですね、今回一番最初の企画を早速いっちゃいましょうかね！ 実はね、あのー告知の時にも言ったんですけども、今日はなんと
Now then! Let's go ahead and start with the very first segment!
Actually, as I mentioned during the announcement, today...
このステージにとあるゲームが召喚されるということで、 一体何のゲームなのか？ちょっとね、何のヒントもなかったんですけども
...a certain game will be summoned to this stage, but what game could it be?
There wasn't any hint at all, but...
コメント欄でね、ちょっと「実はいっ…」あれっ！？当ててる方がいらっしゃったんですよ！ すごいと思って白上何の情報も出してないのに。
...in the chat, someone actually... wait!? Some people guessed it!
I thought it was amazing since I didn't give out any information.
ではではね、えー他の皆さんは一体何を考えているのか分かりませんが！ よーい！しましょー！
Well then, who knows what everyone else is thinking!
Ready, let's go!
好き勝手召喚しよう！ではでは！
Let's summon them however we like! Now then,
出てこーい！うおおお！きたきたきた！
come on out! Whoa! It's here, it's here!
下から！下から来るぞ！うおお！出てこい！出てこい！
From below! It's coming from below! Whoa, come on out! Come on out!
どわー！聞いたー！
Whoa! I heard it!
はい！ということで、なんと、なんと！皆さんね、ゲームセンターで、お馴染みとしてましてしょー！
Yay! And so, guess what! Everyone, you're all familiar with this at the arcade, right?!
大人気の音ゲー、jubeat！なんと今回KONAMIさんに、お願いしたところ…
The super popular rhythm game, Jubeat! When I asked Konami about it this time...
え、アリーナでどうぞ！ということで、持ってきていただきました！ありがとうございます！
they said, "Sure, in the Arena!" and brought it over for us! Thank you so much!
さてさて、しかもこれ、見てください。白上特別仕様で！
Now, now, and look at this. It's made with a special Shirakami design!
なんと作っていただけました、見て。ここで今回のね、こうイラストもあって…
They actually made this for me, look. Here, there are illustrations for this time...
横にも実はステッカーが…いや、ヤッホー！なんこれ、ちょっとヤッホー！
and on the side there are actually stickers... Wait, Yahoo! What is this, seriously, Yahoo!
いやね、トウモロコシで、実は反対側も…あるんですよ。
See, it's corn, and actually the other side has it too.
やー！こちらね、スコ組もようおいで、おれのロゴもあって…
Yay! Over here, Suko-gumi is welcome, my logo is there too...
いや本当、すごいですよ！なんか白上の画面だとみんなのコメントが止まっちゃってる…
Man, it's really amazing! It looks like on Shirakami's screen everyone's comments stopped...
きっとみんな「わー！すごい！」って言ってくれてるはず！はず！はず！たぶん！
I'm sure everyone is saying, "Whoa, amazing!" Must be! Must be! Probably!
あ、更新してくださるかな、もしかして。あ、更新してくれた！わーい！ありがとうございます！
Ah, maybe they updated. Oh, they updated! Yay! Thank you so much!
ゴールデンヤッホーはいらっしゃるよ！ね、今回は、このね、jubeatをやらせていただけるとということで…
Golden Yahoo is here too! See, this time, since we get to play Jubeat...
もう本当に白上、まあね、ちょっとさ、ここ最近なかなゲームセンター行く機会が…
honestly, Shirakami—well, lately I haven't had many chances to go to the arcade...
ない中、ずっとねやり続けてる音ゲーがこのjubeatだったなので、こうやってね、配信できるのがめちゃめちゃ…
so the rhythm game I've kept playing all this time is Jubeat, so being able to stream like this is super...
嬉しいです！夢が叶いました！ありがとうございます！いえーーい！
I'm so happy! My dream came true! Thank you so much! Yay!
いやいやいやいや！なんだね今回はですね、ちょっとjubeatで遊んでいこうと思うんですけども…
Yay yay yay! This time, I thought we'd play around with Jubeat, but...
ええ、こうやって用意していただいたにも関わらず白上あんまり実はうまくがい、うまくないという…完全にエンジョイエンジョイ勢なのでね！
despite them preparing this for us, Shirakami actually isn't very good at it... I'm totally just a casual enjoyer!
あの、ちょっと腕前についてはみなさん、あの…楽しんでるなー、くらいに見ていただけると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
Um, regarding my skill level, everyone, I'd be happy if you just watched while thinking, "She's having fun!" Please treat me well!
では！さっそくやっていきましょう！イエーイ！こんなアリーナステージでやっちゃっていいんですか？
Now! Let's get right into it! Yay! Is it really okay to do this in an Arena stage?
みんながサイリウム振ってくれてる中！ではですね、ちょっと…やっちゃいますか！
While everyone is waving their penlights! Well then, shall we... do it?
はい！では、いきましょう！スタート！うわー！
Alright! Now, let's go! Start! Whoa!
これね、ほんとは、こうやっておきゅ…お金入れて、アミュージメントパスピンして、パスワードを入力して…
This, really, you put money in like this... input your Amusement Pass PIN, enter your password...
やるんですけどもね！うわー、画面もちゃんと映ってる！やったーすごい！
and play, but! Whoa, the screen is showing properly too! Yay, amazing!
え、これ見てください。これ、お金フリーって書いてあるんですけど、これあの連コし放題ってことですか？ねえ、ちょっと連コし放題じゃないですか！やば！
Um, please look at this. It says "Money Free," does this mean you can play continuously as much as you want? Hey, isn't this continuous play?! That's crazy!
ではですね、ちょっと白上の好きな楽曲をね、やっていこうかと思います。まずこの「concon」！concon白上めっちゃ好きで…
Well then, I think I'll play some of Shirakami's favorite songs. First, this "concon"! Shirakami really loves concon...
そう、これキツネなんですよ！キツネなんですよconcon。ちょっとレベル10か、どうしようかな。アドバンスあたりでいいかな。1曲目だし、アドバンスあたりで…
Yeah, this is a fox! It's a fox, concon. Level 10, what should I do? Around Advanced should be fine. It's the first song, so around Advanced...
どうでしょう皆さん？ね、いいですか？いいですか？アドバンスいいですか？
what do you all think? Hey, is that okay? Is that okay? Is Advanced okay?
エクストリームじゃなきゃだめです？え？ど、ど、どっちだろ？アドバンスがエクストリーム…
Does it have to be Extreme? Eh? Wh-wh-which one? Advanced or Extreme...
どっちがいいですか？えく、エクストリームいっちゃう？
which one is good? Shall I go with Extreme?
なんか天の声がエクストリームって言ってる！じゃあ、いきましょう！わあ！
Somehow, a voice from the heavens is saying Extreme! Well then, let's go! Yay!
ちょっと、レベル10なんでできるか怪しいですが！いきましょう！
Level 10 might be a bit sketchy, but let's go!
楽曲はめちゃめちゃ好きなんですよ！ここからスタートだ！
I really love the song! Starting from here!
たたたた…
Tatata...
わあ！たたた…
Whoa! Tatata...
ははは！たたた…
Haha! Tatata...
たたた！
Tatata!
ここほり！
Dig here!
ここ好き！
Love this part!
ここ好きです！
I love this part!
おっ、次々！
Oh, next, next!
ああーっ！
Aah!
助けてっ！
Help me!
やったあ！
Yay!
でもクリア、クリア、クリア！イェイ！
But clear, clear, clear! Yay!
クリア、クリア！イェイ！
Clear, clear! Yay!
やりましたー！
I did it!
ということで、コンコン
And so, CONCON...
いやー
Man...
みんなどうでした？これがユビートやで
How was it everyone? This is Jubeat for ya.
わあ、ありがとうございます！
Waah, thank you very much!
じゃあね、まだ遊んでいいということで
Well then, since I can keep playing,
じゃあね、白髪の好きな曲もう一曲やっちゃおうか
let's play another song I like, Shirakami's favorite!
待って、この子のはナツノオワニとか入ってるよ、みんな
Wait, this one has 'Natsu no Owani' and stuff in it, everyone.
コイメリーナ、いやもう本当にいろんな曲
Koimerina, man really, so many songs...
詰め込んでくださって、もうありがとうございます！
packed in here, thank you so much!
どうしようかな
What should I do?
この順で、曲目、あっ曲、曲、曲、曲名で
In this order, track... ah, song, song, song, by song title,
ええと、どこだったっけかな
um, where was it again?
あ、こっちだ、こっちだ、あったあった。あのー
Ah, it's this way, it's this way, found it. Um...
あった！AREA 51！
Found it! AREA 51!
いやAREA 51めためた好きなんですよ、クロちゃんの曲でね
Man, I freaking love AREA 51, it's Kuro-chan's song,
ということで、AREA 51もね、これさっきよりね、ちょっとレベルが
so, AREA 51 too, the level is a bit lower than the previous one,
1個下なので、ま、きっとやりやすいだろうということで
one level lower, so it'll probably be easier to play,
AREA 51、やっていきましょう！
let's play AREA 51!
いいですね、この待機中のこれすごい好きです
This is great, I really like this waiting screen.
はぁーかっこいい！
Haa, so cool!
かっこいい！
So cool!
さあ、どんどん、どんどん…
Now, keep going, keep going...
どうしよう、どうしよう
What should I do, what should I do?
次もね、難しそうなりょうしー
Next looks difficult too, ryoushii...
いけるか？
Can I do it?
おっ、つながったー！
Oh, full combo!
やばーい！
Oh no!
やったー！イェイ！
Yay! Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
やった、クリア！よっし、もうクリアできればオッケー！
Yay, clear! Alright, as long as I can clear it, it's okay!
クリアできれば！
As long as I clear it!
ぜんぜんまるー！
Totally fine!
さてさて、じゃあねちょっと3曲目もサクッとやっちゃいますか！
Now then, shall we quickly do the 3rd song too!
みんな大好きですよね、エバンスね
Everyone loves Evans, right?
白神も、えーめためた大好きですね
Shirakami too, um, I freaking love it.
よし君の楽曲でございますけども
It's Yoshi-kun's song, though,
ちょっと、エバンスはー、うーん、難しいですけども
Evans is, um, difficult, but
めった楽しい楽曲なのでね、こちらも楽しんでやっていきましょう！
it's a super fun song, so let's enjoy playing this one too!
ダダダダンですね、キリさん
It's dadadadan, Kiri-san.
あっ、うそでしょ！
Ah, you've got to be kidding!
はぁ、たたたん、たんたんたん、ほいっ！
Haa, tatatan, tantantan, hoi!
ここがんばれ！
Hang in there here!
自分に全部刻んどいて何キョトンなくなりますね
You carve it all into yourself, and then you act all blank.
さあ皆さん、DJをしたことお馴染みの大回転
Now everyone, the familiar great rotation of doing DJ—
たた、たたたたたたたた、たたたたたたたた
Ta-ta, ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta...
うわー！
Whoa!
あー！どっちも繋がらない！
Ahh! Neither of them connected!
あー間違えた！たたたたたたたたたたたたたたたた
Ah, I messed up! Ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta...
あー！たたたたたたたたたたたたたたたた
Ahh! Ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta...
たた、たたたたたたたた、たたたたたたたた
Ta-ta, ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta...
はっ！
Ha!
たた、たたたたたたたた、たたたたたたたた
Ta-ta, ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta...
さあ、起き！あー！あー、たたたたたたたたたたたたたた
Now, wake up! Ahh! Ah, ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta...
そうそうそうそう、どんどんどんどんどんどん
That's right, keep going, keep going!
ドン！
Boom!
いやあ、いい曲！懐かしいですね。
Man, what a good song! So nostalgic.
でもクリアはした。
But I cleared it!
クリア！クリアしたからオッケーです。見事な青色、まさにソーダでしたね。
Cleared! I cleared it, so it's okay. A magnificent blue, truly like soda.
ということでありがとうございました。お、3曲設定ですか？お、3曲設定だった！わーい！
And with that, thank you very much! Oh, a 3-song setting? Oh, it was a 3-song setting! Yay!
いや、楽しいですね。いや、いいですね、jubeatと。ね。
Man, this is fun. Yeah, Jubeat is great, isn't it?
さてさて。
Now, now.
ちょ、待ってよ。ちょっとまだ連コしていらしいので、そう連コしちゃおうかな。ぽっぽっぽっ。
Wait a minute. It seems people are still continuously playing, so maybe I'll do a consecutive play too. Pop, pop, pop.
いや、いいですね、こうやって。こうやって、後ろを気にせず連コしていい、ゲームセンター。ホロライブ、ゲームセンターホロライブですけども。
Man, it's nice like this. Being able to do consecutive plays without worrying about what's behind you, at a game center. Hololife, Game Center Hololife, though.
そろそろね、あの曲もやってみましょうか。
Time for us to try that song too, soon.
実はこのjubeatですね、シャッターデザインだけじゃないんです、皆さん！入ってる曲もなんと、特別仕様なんです。
Actually, this Jubeat, you know, it's not just the shutter design, everyone! The included songs are also special editions!
さてさて、ちょっとね、最初やらかしちゃって、チラ見えしちゃったので、あれ？プレイヤーの人、あれ？と思ったかもしれないんですけども。
Now, now, I kind of messed up at first and accidentally spoiled a glimpse, so you players might have thought, "Huh?" but—
行きましょうか。しょっ。
Shall we go? Shh.
なんかキツネマークがある。見てみなほら、なんかキツネマークが。なんだこのキツネマークは？
There's some fox mark. Look, see, there's a fox mark. What is this fox mark?
行きましょう！でい！
Let's go! Hey!
なんと！なんとオリ曲が入ってます！すごい！鬼神も入ってる！セイファ！
What?! Our original song is in here! Amazing! Onigami is also in! Sayfan!
すいません、バダネーション。
Excuse me, Thunder Nation.
わくわくバビデイ！
Waku Waku Babidey!
ねえ、ハピネスキングワールドも入ってる！やばい！
Hey, Happiness King World is in here too! No way!
いや、これはちょっとやっていかなきゃいけませんね。
Man, we gotta play this one.
では最初、このKINGワールド行くか。98。
Well then, first, let's go with this King World. 98.
あ、セイファよりキングワールドのがむずい、あり。
Ah, King World is harder than Sayfan, plausible.
ちょっと、チラ見え完全初見なんですけど、行ってみましょう。
Well, it's my complete first time seeing a glimpse, but let's go try it.
よし！いくぞ！
Alright! Let's go!
はあー！緊張した！どんな譜面なんだ。
Haaah! I was so nervous! What kind of chart is this?
リーンさん、キリンさん。
Lean-san, Kirin-san.
ゴー！
Go!
幽閉 利口 逝く前に
Locking up the clever one before they die
ユーヘイじゃ利口に難儀ダーリング
you, hey, you know that it's a pain to get you to be obedient, darling
幽閉 ストップ 知ってないし
Don't lock me up! It's not like I knew.
勘弁にしろっていってんな惨忍
Give me a break! You're so cruel.
人様願う 欠片のアイロニ 誰が望む 無機質なような
The wishes of the people feel like scraps of irony, everyone's wishing for the same mechanical thing.
一歩先に始めていたような 先が見えないヴァージン ハッピーショー
A virgin happy show you want to get in on before everyone else, where nobody knows what's going to happen next.
無いの一新にお願い一つ 愛も変わらずおまけに
I don't have a single brand-new wish: the same as ever, and on top of that—
ワーニング ワーニング
Warning, warning!
無いのあなたにお願い一つ 張り詰めた思い込め
I put all my stress into a wish for you.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side!
歯をむき出して パッパッパ 照れくさいね
Baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa, this is so embarrassing!
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side!
歯を突き出して パッパッパ
Let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa!
ハハ、ユーアーキング
Haha, you are king!
ユーアーキング
You are king!
無邪気に遊ぶ 期待 期待のダーリングダーリング
Playing innocently, you're the darling, darling that I've been wishing and hoping for.
健気に微笑む 痛いの痛いの消える
When you laugh admirably, all of my pain disappears.
無様にしねる 苦い思いもなくなって
And I'm able to die clumsily, my bitter feelings fading too.
ラララブ ラッタッタ
Lo-lo-love, ra-ta-ta!
嫌い嫌いの最低泣いてダウン
I hate it, i hate it, it's the worst - I burst into tears and I'm down for the count.
毎毎回新にお願い一つ
Just as always, here's a brand-new wish:
愛も変わらずピックアップの
the same as ever, there's no picked-out...
ワーニング ワーニング
Warning, warning!
無いのあなたにお願い一つ 張り詰めた思い込め
I put all my stress into a wish for you.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side!
歯をむき出して パッパッパ 邪魔くさいね
Baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa, this is so bothersome!
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side!
歯を突き出して パッパッパ
Let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa!
ハハ、ユーアーキング
Haha, you are king!
ユーアーキング
You are king!
繋ぎ止めていて 世界で どれだけ君を守ってやれるの？
How much of the world can I protect by holding you together?
天の邪鬼とアンバランス
An imbalance with a contrarian spirit.
溢れそうさ大変、でも異常気象もいいそう
It's about to overflow, so troublesome, but even abnormal weather sounds nice.
こんにちは、バじゃ無い。退屈はカスタマイズ
Hello, that's not it. Boredom is customized.
楽しくなりそうな学び、これです
Learning that looks like it's going to be fun, this is it!
先ずは、
First of all...
幽閉 利口 逝く前に
Imprisoned, clever, before passing on,
ユーヘイじゃりこうに難儀ダーリン
it's tough to be clever, darling.
幽閉 ストップ 知ってないし
Stopping imprisonment, I don't know it,
勘弁にしといてなんて惨忍
have mercy on me, how cruel.
人様願う 欠片のアイロニ
The irony of fragments that people wish for,
だれもが願う 無機質なような
something like the inorganic that everyone wishes for,
一歩足先に 始めていたような
like wanting to start one step ahead.
先が見えない ヴァージン ハッピーショー
A virgin happy show where you can't see ahead,
無いのか 新たにお願い一つ
isn't there one new request?
愛も変わらず おまけに
Love remains unchanged, plus a bonus,
ワーニング ワーニング
warning, warning.
無いのか あなたにお願い一つ
One request to you, if any.
よしよしよかった！
Yes! I made it!
やばすぎた！
That was way too close!
いやでもすごく楽しい譜面でした、ありがとうございます！
Man, that was a really fun chart though, thank you!
めちゃいい！
Super good!
キングワールドよかったな、あの…シッポのなんか尿加減が出てた、すごっ！
King World was nice, um... you could really feel the tail vibes, amazing!
いや、ありがとうございます、これ！
Man, thank you for this!
じゃあ、続いてどうしようかな、ちょっと簡単なのにしますか。
Now then, what should I do next? Shall I pick an easy one?
ワクワクエブリデイ、とまらないでしょ！
Wakuwaku Everyday, you can't stop it!
じゃあちょっとワクワクエブリデイもいきますか！
Well then, shall we go with Wakuwaku Everyday too!
よし！
Alright!
ここちよいはれぞーな
A pleasant clearing...
今日は何をしてあそぼう
What shall we play today?
なみのカワラナイ
Waves unchanging,
雲を追いかけてみよう
let's try chasing the clouds.
はしゃぎまわって疲れて
Running around and getting tired,
おなかもすいて寝転んで
getting hungry and lying down.
明日はもっといい日になりそう、いっしょだよ！
Tomorrow looks like an even better day, we're together!
いつもキラキラ毎日とまらない！
Always sparkling every day, won't stop!
やりたいことぜんぶ、あそびつくしても！
Even if we play out all the things we want to do!
世界はまだ知らないことたくさんあるけど
There are still so many things the world doesn't know, but...
きみとぎゅっとして手を繋いでころん
Hugging you tightly and holding hands, rolling over,
こんなときもきみといっしょならもっと笑えるといいよね！
it'd be great if we could smile even more when I'm with you like this!
よろしくどうぞ！
Best regards!
なんだこれは？おい！おい！
What is this? Hey! Hey!
あ、音符マークみたいになった今のは。はっはー！
Ah, that just became like a note mark. Haha!
え、でもSいけた、やった！
Eh, but I got an S, yay!
なんか最後音符マークみたいなのがなんかピュッて譜面で、すごい！
Like, at the end, that note mark thing just zoomed across the chart, amazing!
いやーということで、ちょっとね、3曲やらせてもらいましたが！
Man, so anyway, we played three songs!
いや譜面がなかなかに、なかなかにいい感じに、ふふふ、譜面でしたね！
Man, the charts were quite, quite nicely... hehehe, charts!
さてさて、セファンファーレ、そうだ残ってました。
Now, now, Se-Fanfare, right, that was left.
まだセファンファーレがあるんだ！
There's still Se-Fanfare!
セファンファーレちょっとこれノーツ、つまりすぎ、つまりすぎっていませんかこれ、うえー、ねえ！
Se-Fanfare, aren't these notes a bit too packed, too packed, ugh, hey!
ちょっと、ワクワクエブ、あ、やばっ、キングワールドの方がやばかったか！
Wait, Wakuwaku Eve-, ah, oops, was King World even more intense?!
詰まりにつまってますね。
It's packed to the brim.
まあまあBPM170だからきっと大丈夫でしょう、うん！
Well, BPM is 170 so it should be fine, yeah!
うーっ、go!
Woo, go!
いーえい！はい！はい！
Yeah! Yes! Yes!
うーっ、こんこんっ！
Woo, Kon-kon!
foo! せーのっ! are you ready? go!
Foo! Ready, set, are you ready? Go!
ほーっとひと息 お茶ですよ
Take a deep breath, it's tea time!
いつもの場所から 元気にいこーぜーで ご挨拶
From my usual spot, full of energy, greetings!
おっほこんできてすよー！
Good morning-con-desu-yo!
始めましょう！
Let's begin!
おしゃべりをして ゲームと過ごす
Chatting and spending time with games,
そんな毎日が 愛しくて
such days are so dear.
あれもこれも 手を出したくなりりがちです
I tend to reach out for this and that.
歌とかステージは まだまだ恥ずかしい だけど
Singing and stages are still a bit embarrassing, but
支え合って ほら届けますよ この声を
supporting each other, look, I'll deliver this voice to you!
say! yeah!
ほらその顔上げて みんなで手を取れば
Look, raise your face, if everyone holds hands,
dive! foo! まだまだ道の途中 世界を越えよう
Dive! Foo! We're still on the way, let's cross the world!
せーのっ!
Ready, set!
say! yeah!
ほら推しごとま止まらない 全力ですから！
Look, my oshi work never stops, because I'm giving it my all!
夢を書きかえては 追いかけ続けよう
If you rewrite your dreams, keep chasing them,
ともに はい！ 繋ぐ はい！
together, yes! Connecting, yes!
ファンファーレ
Fanfare!
いーえい！はい！はい！
Yeah! Yes! Yes!
ちょーっとやわ示した時でも
Even when I make a little mistake,
もう大丈夫!
it's okay already!
気持ち切り替えて
Switch your mood,
ぼーっとしてしまう 昼下がりは
for the lazy afternoon,
ひるこんできてすよー！
it's hiru-con-desu-yo!
背伸びをして お腹へったらすぐモグモグと
Stretching out, when I get hungry, I go munch-munch right away.
ふゆ！はい！はい！うん、ここん！うん！
Fuyu! Yes! Yes! Yup, kokon! Yup!
ここん！はい！ふう、ふう、ふう、のど、のど！
Kokon! Yes! Fu, fu, fu, throat, throat!
えー！
Eh?!
はい！はい！うん、ここん！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yup, kokon! Yes! Yes!
ワン、ツー、え？星の、ここにこなかった、これんかい！
One, two, eh? The star didn't come here, is that it?!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ねぇ、さあ途中ね、エフがあったんですけど、エフが
Hey, wait, halfway through there was an F, but the F...
すごっ！
Amazing!
え、なんとかギリギリクリアでございます。え、キングワールドの
Eh, somehow I barely cleared it. Eh, compared to King World...
よりちょっと難しかった印象がありました。
it felt a bit harder.
エフありましたね、すごい！という事で！
There was an F, amazing! So,
ありがとうございました！
thank you very much!
さてさてさて、じゃああとね、2曲ぐらいやってもしよいということなので、ちょっとコメント欄からリクエストあればやっていこうかなと思います。
Now, now, since we can do about two more songs, if there are requests in the comment section, I thought I'd do them.
はーい、なんかツイッターのトレンド1位？わあ、すごい待って！
Ha-ii, wait, Twitter trend #1? Wow, wait!
早い！早い！みんな、ツイッターのトレンド1位ですって、ありがとうございます！わあーい！
Fast! Fast! Everyone, it's #1 on Twitter trends, thank you so much! Yay!
じゃあじゃあちょっとね、1曲は白上ももう1曲やりたいなるので、もう1曲ちょっと、リクエストあればやっていこうかなと思います。
Now then, since I want to do one more song myself, I thought I'd take requests for one more song.
1曲はちょっと、どうしようかな？ちょっと曲順でやりたいのが、もうどうしても配信でこれが言いたくて
For one song, let's see, what should I do? In song order, I wanted to say this on stream no matter what,
こちらですね、あの、美味しいお米の炊き方、そしてお米を食べることによるソロ効果という楽曲でございまして
is this one, "How to Cook Delicious Rice" and "The Solo Effects of Eating Rice"...
みんなでね、お米、お米米もね、ちょっとやっていこうかなと、思います。
Let's all do rice, rice-rice too, I think.
おにぎりもね、欲しい！じゃあもう1曲はおにぎりにしましょうか。
I want onigiri too! Well, let's make the other song onigiri.
ちょっと、お米していきましょう、みんな！行きましょうでは、お米だ！
Let's do rice everyone! Let's go, it's rice!
ごはんはいすごいよ なんだも合うよ ホカホカ
Rice is amazing, it goes with everything, hot hot
ごはんはいなすごいよ なんだも合うよ ホカホカ
ごはんはいなすごいよ なんだも合うよ
Rice is amazing, it goes with everything...
ごはんはいなすごいよ
Rice is amazing,
ごはんはいなすごいよ なんだも合うよ ホカホカ
Rice is amazing, it goes with everything, hot hot
ごはんはいなすごいよ なんだも合うよ
Rice is amazing, it goes with everything,
ごはんはいなすごいよ おかず！
Rice is amazing, it's a side dish!
ありがとうございました！お米、お米米、コメント欄も米になっておる、ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Rice, rice-rice, the comment section has turned into rice too, thank you!
こちらね、あの、ぜひぜひ皆さん、ええ、覚えていただきたいですね。お米、お米米って
Everyone, please, um, remember this. Rice, rice-rice...
他にもですね、実は色々ジョマンダとかもやりたかったんですけども、そう、まあね、ちょっと時間の都合であと1曲、じゃあ、やっちゃいますか。え、どうしよう？
Also, actually, I wanted to do Joman-da and various other things, but well, due to time constraints, let's do one more song. Eh, what should I do?
バカサレンダー行きます？バカサレンダー！バカサレンダー行きますか、どうせならね！
Shall we go with Baka Sarendar? Baka Sarendar! Shall we go with Baka Sarendar, since we're at it!
せっかく入れてもらいましたし、バカサレンダー行きましょうでは！よーう！
Since you added it for me, let's go with Baka Sarendar! Yo!
いぇい！よしよし。
Yay! Alright, alright.
バカサレンダー、いったいどんな譜面なのか。バカサレンダーも、ご！よし、ほい！
Baka Sarendar, what kind of chart is it anyway. Baka Sarendar too, go! Alright, ho!
おお！た、た、た、た、た、た、た、た、た、た、た、た！
Oh! Ta, ta, ta, ta, ta, ta, ta, ta, ta, ta, ta, ta!
手探りじゃ進めない 私たち
We can't move forward fumbling around,
みんなですすもう
Let's all move forward together!
間違ってもいいよ 答え合わせは難しくないよね
It's okay to make mistakes, checking answers isn't that hard, right?
迷うなら出せる答え いつも強い絆の
If you're lost, the answer you can always produce is a strong bond...
メロディ
...melody.
ひとりきりじゃないよ 迷わないよ
You're not alone, you won't get lost,
もう一回！
One more time!
挑戦者へ サプライズさせてよ 鳴らない 音のリズムを合わせて 上手に
To the challengers, let's make a surprise, matching the rhythm of the sound, skillfully...
私たちがナンバーワン いつだってオレは これまでも ここからもずっと
We are number one, always, me, from now on and forever from here too...
ワクワク続いてくよ
The excitement will continue!
見果てぬの扉 そろそろ 開けていこう
The unseen door, it's about time we open it.
怖がらなくていいよ 下がれ でも一人じゃないよね
You don't have to be afraid, step back, but you're not alone, right?
迷ってもいいよ 探して 良い道も イベントらしい
It's okay to get lost, searching for a good path feels like an event too!
命が確実にあったの 祈り祈り で負けない号令
Life was definitely there, a commanding order not to lose in prayer and prayer, final go!
広いけど まあるい宇宙
It's vast, but it's a round universe.
そのあとは続いてくよ
After that, it will continue!
おおー！ すごい！
Ohh! Amazing!
こういう終わり方なんですね
So that's how it ends.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much!
いやあ どうしたら イエス行きたかったなぁ
Man, what should I do, I wanted to go to YES...
ということで はい、ありがとうございましたー！
And with that, yes, thank you very much!
ちなみにですけども、今日遊んだ 白上のおなじ曲
By the way, today we played Shirakami's same song...
ね、あのマリーちゃんとかの楽曲もあります、みおとかもありますけども、なんと全国のユビートで
You know, there are songs like Marie's, Mio's and others too, but get this, in Jubeat nationwide...
遊べるようになります！ イエーイ！
You'll be able to play them! Yay!
すごーい！ こちらですね、全6曲が収録されます！
Amazing! Here, a total of 6 songs will be included!
期間が、アプリの方が7日の朝11時頃から！
The period starts on the 7th around 11:00 AM for the app!
そして、アーケード版は近日実装予定です！ イエーイ！
And the arcade version is scheduled for implementation soon! Yay!
ついに！ 我々の楽曲がユビートで遊べる日がきたー！ ありがとうございます！
Finally! The day has come when our songs can be played in Jubeat! Thank you so much!
ね、アプリが7日、アーケード版は近日実装なので、よければねユビート公式さんのほう見ていただければいいのかな？
You know, the app is on the 7th, and the arcade version is coming soon, so you can check out Jubeat's official account if you like!
それか、白上のほうでも呟きます。 お願いしまーす！ やった！ 嬉しい！
Or I'll tweet about it too. Please check it out! Yay! I'm so happy!
いやもうほんとに 白上 お手上げの中でユビートの歴史が一番長いので、めちゃめちゃ本当に嬉しいです。コナミさんありがとうございます！
Seriously, among all of Shirakami's undertakings, Jubeat's history is the longest, so I'm truly, incredibly happy. Thank you, Konami!
いやあ、もうなんか 今後出るオリ曲とかホロメンの他の楽曲も入れていただきたいですね。よし、よければ入れてください。お願いします。
Man, I'd love for them to include future original songs and other Hololive members' songs too. Well, please add them if you'd like. Please.
ではではね、ちょっとちょっと名残惜しいですけども、まだまだやりたーい！ 家に筐体が欲しい！ ガチで欲しいです家に筐体が。
Well then, it's a bit bittersweet, but I still want to play more! I want an arcade cabinet at home! I seriously want one at home.
ねえ、まだまだ見せたい企画もございますので、引き続き こんなバラエティをお楽しみください！
Right, we still have more planning to show you, so please continue to enjoy this kind of variety show!
それでは、どうぞー！
Now then, here we go!
フブキは朝起きてら フブラになっていた コーン
Fubuki woke up in the morning and had turned into Fubura... Corn.
フブキは慌てて すこん部達に 報告をしました あ、フブラだ あれ、フブキちゃん？
Fubuki panicked and reported it to the Sukonbu squad. Ah, it's Fubura. Huh, Fubuki-chan?
Hi, Friend! コーン コーン
Hi, Friend! Corn! Corn!
ですが すこん部にも 原因はわからない という結論に
But the Sukonbu squad concluded that even they didn't know the cause.
オコマリノヨウデスネ
You seem to be in trouble.
デーーーン ゴーーーン ミテイル先輩！
Daaamnn! Gonn! Mitairu-senpai!
ペラペラ この古文書 ホロ＝ペディア によれば 解放のダンスを踊ればもとに戻れるらしい ゴーン
Flipping, flipping... According to this ancient document, Holopedia, if you dance the dance of liberation, you can return to normal. Gonn.
コーン コーン コーン
Corn! Corn! Corn!
よし 画面の向こうのキミも一緒に踊ろう！！
Alright, you on the other side of the screen, let's dance together!!
こうして無事元の姿に戻ったフブキをみんなでお祝いしたのでした
And so, everyone celebrated Fubuki safely returning to her original form.
わあーい！やったー！
Yay! Hooray!
音が……遠いのデス
The sound is... far away.
しかしこの事件は裏でおるやんけが暗躍していた
However, behind this incident, Oruyanke was operating in the shadows.
つづく（ウッ）
To be continued... (Ugh!)
はい、フブキちゃんのボドゲすこん部ー！
Welcome to Fubuki-buchou's Board Game Sukonbu!
よく来ましたね新入部員の皆さん
Welcome, new club members!
部員なんですか？私たち
Are we really club members?
部員そうですよ？
Of course you are!
フブキさんが誕生日だから来たんですけど
We came because it's Fubuki's birthday, though.
違う！違う！セルフ誕生日会！？
No, no! A self-birthday party?!
違うよ〜！
That's not it!
今日は皆とボドゲがやりたくて呼んだんです
I invited you all today because I wanted to play board games together!
ボドゲやりましょうやりましょう！
Let's play board games!
遊ぶのはこちらのボードゲーム！
The game we're playing is this board game!
オジサンメッセージ！
"Ojisan Message!"
オジサンになって気持ち悪いメッセージを作ってください
You have to become an ojisan and create creepy messages!
気持ち悪いメッセージか
A creepy message, huh.
まずは皆に同じカードが配られます
First, everyone receives the same cards.
まるまるちゃん、おはようでちゅ、バブバブと言った感じですね。
Like "Marumaru-chan, good morning-chu, bubu bubu."
オジサンが送ってくるメッセージが両面に書かれてます。両面ですね。
The messages sent by the ojisan are written on both sides. Both sides, you see.
この基本カードに加えてランダムなメッセージが書かれたオジサンカードを組み合わせていきます。
In addition to these basic cards, we combine random message cards to make ojisan messages.
実際にちょっと例文として白髪作ってみました。
I actually made a sample sentence as Shirakami.
こちらのおじさんでございます。どれどれ？
Here is the ojisan. Let's see...
みおちゃん？どうしてもって言うなら今度とっておきのプレゼントしてあげるよ。にゃんにゃん。興奮してきたぞ〜！
Mio-chan? If you insist, next time I'll give you a special present. Nyan nyan. I'm getting excited~!
マシラれてんじゃねえか！
You're being harassed!
なるほどね。まあこんな感じのちょっと気持ち悪いなっていうものを作っていきます。
I see. So we'll make something a bit creepy like this...
1人が女性役、3人がおじさん役として、で3人がおじさんになってね、その子にメッセージを送りましょう。
One person plays the female role, and three play ojisan roles, sending messages to the girl.
最もブロックしたいメッセージを1人選んでください。
Choose the message you most want to block!
ブロックされたら勝ちですっていうことと思うんですけども。
If you get blocked, you win, or so I think, but...
ちょっと失礼してもらっていいですか。
Excuse me for a moment.
ななんですか？急におじさんすか？何ですか？いっしょーい！
What is it? Suddenly an ojisan? What is this? Together!
フブおじ！？
Fubu-ojisan?!
なんやて？やーだ！おじさん！
What's this? No way! An ojisan!
おじさんになる人みんなヒゲつけていきましょう。
Everyone who's becoming an ojisan, let's put on mustaches.
ヒゲカモーン！生えろー！やだー！
Mustache come on! Grow! No way!
だって！可愛いよ！
Eh, but! Cute!
もうお嫁にいけないわ！
I can't get married anymore!
なんだこれ！なんか可愛いよ！吾輩って感じだよ、すごい！
What is this?! It's kind of cute! It gives off a "Wagahai" vibe, amazing!
ということでじゃ皆さん。おじさんになってください。変なおじさんと繋がっちゃったよ〜！一緒にコミケ行こう話しただけなのに！
So everyone, please become ojisan. I got connected with a weird ojisan~! We only talked about going to Comiket together!
ちょっとリアル、おっとタブかしてんね、そんなことないよ！
A bit too realistic. Whoops, is that taboo? No such thing!
かわいいな。オッケーできました。
So cute. Okay, done.
そしてどうなるかな。まあみんなめっちゃ考えてますね。そして、
Now, how will it turn out? Well, everyone is thinking hard. Now,
ヤバイ単語が出てこないことを祈りますね。
I pray no dangerous words come out.
よし、これでいいかしらね。お、オッケー。
Alright, is this good? Oh, okay.
おくちゃん、できました。
Oku-chan, done.
で最初はじゃまりおじ行っときましょうかね。さあ、とびっきりのフブちゃんに送信と。ネットリしてるすごい。
First, let's go with Mari-oji. Now, sending to wonderful Fubu-chan. So sticky.
フブちゃん。ボインボイン。プリンプリン。一緒にイキたいな！ 3日連絡ないなぁ。みて欲しいな。連絡欲しいな。逮捕しちゃうぞ！
Fubu-chan. Boin boin. Purin purin. I want to go together! No contact for 3 days. I want you to see. I want contact. I'm going to arrest you!
すごい！ヤバイこのおじさん！普通にヤバイおじさんだ！
Amazing! This ojisan is dangerous! This is a normally dangerous ojisan!
一緒にイキたいんじゃ！何してんのおじさん？
I want to go together! What are you doing, ojisan?
でも2つ「いな」付いてるのもヤバイですね。いい踏んでる、いい踏んでる。
But having two "ina"s attached is also dangerous. Good rhyme, good rhyme.
かまって欲しいな。フブちゃんにかまって貰いたいぞ！
I want you to pay attention to me. I want Fubu-chan to pay attention to me!
じゃ続いては、ミオおじ行っときますか。オッケー。ちょっとね元気系おじさんかなって思います。
Next, let's go with Mio-oji. Okay. I think it's an energetic type of ojisan.
こんばんわき毛！！車買ったンダ。〇〇ちゃん、早く会いたいな。旅館に泊まるのはどうカナ？おじさん、温めてア・ゲ・ル。ハッスルハッスル！
Good evening armpit hair!! I bought a car. Marumaru-chan, I want to see you soon. How about staying at a ryokan? Ojisan will warm you up. Hustle hustle!
こんばんわき毛ずるいだろ！わき毛ずるいな。確かに元気系のおじさんですね。
Good evening armpit hair is so unfair! Armpit hair is unfair. Indeed, it's an energetic ojisan.
じゃ続いて、ラポジ。フブちゃん、待っててね。ネットリしてる。
Next, Lapu-oji. Fubu-chan, wait for me. So sticky.
〇〇ちゃん。公園でバナナ食べて朝まで寝かせないゾ！ここだけの話だけど、おじさんが若かった頃は、富士山。
Marumaru-chan. Eat bananas at the park and I won't let you sleep until morning! Just between us, when ojisan was young, Mount Fuji.
どういうこと！？説明してみろ。
What does that mean?! Explain yourself.
なんというか、あれだよね。なんか自分がやったギャグの説明させられるよりきついこと無い
I mean, having to explain a joke you made yourself is literally the worst.
それでは、じゃあこの中でね、一番ブロックしたいと思ったおじさんは
So then, out of all of us, the ojisan we wanted to block the most is...
マリンおじです！
Marine-ojisan!
おじさんをおかしい…
Ojisan is acting weird...
1週間…1週間連絡来ないんだぁ。
You haven't contacted me in a whole week...
やだ、まりおじ、気持ち悪い…
Ew, Marine-ojisan is so creepy...
一緒に、イキたいな！
Let's reach climax together!
キモすぎ！
So gross!
一人で行くのはおじさんさみしいよ！
It's lonely for an ojisan to go alone!
こわいよおじさん！
That's scary, ojisan!
それではじゃあ、このおじさんブロックです！
Well then, this ojisan is getting blocked!
うわぁ、どうしようかなぁ
Oh man, what should I do?
うわぁ！！フブキおじさん
Whoa!! Fubuki-ojisan
マリンちゃん、お耳立ってるよ！あっはは！
Marine-chan, your ears are perking up! Haha!
ラプおじ、やっとかないでくださいよ！
Lap-ojisan, don't do that!
真剣なラプおじ可愛いね、ちょっと！
A serious Lap-ojisan is so cute!
もうやだぁ、やだ！
No way, stop it!
おっけー、送り終わった？
Okay, you finished sending?
送り終わりました！
Finished sending!
はい、みんな完成ということでね
Alright, everyone's done, so...
それではじゃあ、ミオおじのメッセージから見ていこうかなぁ。ちょっと
Let's take a look at Mio-ojisan's messages first. Let's see...
マリンちゃん、綺麗だね✨
Marine-chan, you're so pretty ✨
ぎゅっ❤️チュウ💋
Hug ❤️ Kiss 💋
匂いかいっちゃった❤️
I ended up sniffing you ❤️
とびきりの！もっこりしちゃう💋
An extraordinary one! I'm getting all horned up 💋
どうしてくれるんだぁ。もっこりしっ
What are you gonna do about this? Getting all horned—
今日お泊まりしちゃおうかなぁ。同棲…
Maybe I'll stay over today. Moving in together...
うわあ、もっこりしちゃったんだ
Whoa, he got all horned up.
匂い、匂いでもっこりしちゃったおじさんね。なるほど
An ojisan who gets horned up just from the smell. I see.
いいじゃないですか、ねぇ、ねぇ！これはなかなか面白いし
Isn't this great? Right, right! This is pretty funny, and...
なんかフブキおじもなんか書き込んでるな
Looks like Fubuki-ojisan is typing something too.
じゃあ、ちょっと行きましょうかね。フブキから、フブキおじ流そう。よっ
Well then, let's check it out. Let's play Fubuki-ojisan's. Here we go.
おはよ〜チュウ！！
Morning~ Kiss!!
マリンちゃん、って初手初手チュー。今日から連休だね✨
Marine-chan, right off the bat with a kiss. Starting consecutive holidays today ✨
はは(*^^* )ん？マリンちゃんのエッチな画像
Haha(*^^*) Hmm? Marine-chan's lewd image.
マリンちゃん！悪い子だな〜！ガオー❤️
Marine-chan! You're a bad girl~! Grr ❤️
え、ちょっと待って、その隙間でマリンがエッチな画像送ってるてい？
Wait a second, in that gap, you're pretending Marine sent a lewd image?
送ってて送ってて！悪い子だな〜！
She sent it, she sent it! You're such a bad girl~!
ふぶちゃん、やらかしたね！マリンからエッチな画像送ってんのにマリンがブロックしないじゃない！
Fubu-chan, you messed up! You're sending lewd images from Marine, but Marine isn't blocking you!
たしかに！これはブロックされないですよ！やばい、やばい！
True! You wouldn't get blocked for this! This is bad, bad!
あ、でとなんか、ラプおじからもなんか…あちょっと、きてるわこれ。恥ずかしいけどマリンちゃん本命だから送っちゃうから。本命なのエッチしちゃったんだ
Oh, and also, Lap-ojisan also sent something... Ah wait, it's here. It's embarrassing, but since Marine-chan is my true love, I'll send it. Because she's my true love, we had sex.
恋しちゃったんだ❤️体の相性も✨スケベおじさんです！
I fell in love ❤️ The body chemistry is great too ✨ I'm a pervy ojisan!
にかく会って話そうよ。手取り足取り何取り？
Anyway, let's meet and talk. What kind of hand-holding?
何取り？どうしよっか？
What kind? What should we do?
既読も未読も気にしないヨ！！
I don't care about read or unread receipts!!
なんでやねん！どう？
What the heck! How is it?
未読も既読も気にしないこのおおらかなアピール
This big-hearted appeal of not caring about read or unread messages.
はい、ということでね、すべてのおメッセージを、おじさんたちのメッセージ見ましたと！はい、どうですか？
Alright, so we've seen all the messages from the ojisan! So, what do you think?
ラプおじは、未読も既読も気にしないからこのまま無視して…
Lap-ojisan doesn't care about read or unread, so we'll just ignore him...
フブおじは、マリンのエッチな画像を持ってるからキルタブ外いかちいな…
Fubu-ojisan has Marine's lewd images, so killing him off is dangerous...
ということで、ミオおじブロックします！
So, we're blocking Mio-ojisan!
なんか嬉しいのやら嬉しくないのやら！いぇーい！
I don't know if I should be happy or not! Yay!
マリンの匂いでもっこりしないでよ！
Don't get all horned up from Marine's smell!
じゃあちなみに一番おじさんっぽくないメッセージは誰？
By the way, whose message felt the least like an ojisan?
えー、ミオおじっぽかったけど、そうだね
Mio felt like one, but yeah.
ラプラスが、なんか若干会話不得意みたいな感じ
Laplus seemed kind of awkward at holding a conversation.
なんかメッセージの脈絡がなかったというか、おじさんっぽくないていうか、会話ができてなくて意味不明だったのね。なるほどね
Like, there was no flow to the messages, or rather it didn't feel like an ojisan, the conversation wasn't happening and it was just nonsense. I see.
いやぁちょっとなぁ、どう返信すべきなんだろうねこういうのとかってね
Man, oh man, how should one even reply to stuff like this?
もう見たら負けみたいなところあるんだけど、ちょっと気になりはしちゃうんだよなぁ
It feels like looking at it means you lose, but I still get curious.
で、できたぞ！おっ
Alright, I'm done! Oh.
ミオちゃんに送っちゃお。ちょっとやばい
I'll send it to Mio-chan. This is kind of bad.
フブおじもいけたぞ！
Fubu-ojisan got it done too!
フブおじからも連絡来てる！
Messages coming from Fubu-ojisan too!
ミオちゃんのこと絶対落とすぞ！この文章で
I'm definitely going to win Mio-chan over! With this text.
よしできた！よしできた
Alright, I'm done! Alright, I'm done.
じゃあちょっとフブおじから見ていこうかな
Well then, let's take a look at Fubu-ojisan's.
フブおじからでいいですか？
Is it okay to start with Fubu-ojisan?
なんでだ！
Why?!
じゃあミオちゃんに送っちゃおかな。これでOK!っと
Well then, I'll send it to Mio-chan. Perfect, done!
ミオちゃん。興奮してきたっちゃ。トロトロの
Mio-chan. I'm getting all excited. Melt-in-your-mouth...
若いエキス欲しいなぁ〜✨〜♪えへへ
I want that young extract~ ✨~♪ Ehehe
以上、スケブおじさんでした！ミオちゃん、許してチョンマゲ✨
That's all from sketchpad ojisan! Mio-chan, forgive me with a topknot ✨
誕生日おめでとう！お仕事がんばってね✨
Happy birthday! Good luck with work ✨
だいぶまともだな！
That's way too normal!
それで無視されてる？うちのエキス渡したくないよお！
And you're getting ignored for that? I don't want to give away my extract!
フブキさんなんじゃなかったでしょ！
Fubuki-san, it wasn't like that at all!
はい、じゃあ次マリオジ！はいマリオジはミオちゃんに送っちゃうぞ！
Alright, next is Marine-ojisan! Alright, Marine-ojisan is gonna send it to Mio-chan!
ミオちゃん。構ってほしいなぁ〜。ミオちゃん。ムチムチのパーフェクト✨
Mio-chan. I want some attention~. Mio-chan. Chubby and perfect ✨
エロエロの罪！鼻血ブー！！暴れ馬ヒヒーン！
Sin of lewdness! Nosebleed splash!! Wild horse hee-haw!
来週の土曜空いてる？
Are you free next Saturday?
暴れ馬ヒヒーン！？
Wild horse hee-haw!?
最高だよミオちゃんは！やばいよ
Mio-chan, you're the best! This is wild.
じゃあ続いては、じゃあ最後はラプおじ！
Next up, and finally, Lap-ojisan!
一番最初にメッセージを送ったのに一番最後に見られなきゃいけないんだ
I sent the first message, but I get to be last?
いくよ
Here we go.
今いくつだっけ!?
How many right now?!
おじさん我慢できないよ
Uncle can't hold back anymore!
おジサン警察です
It's Uncle Police!
あ、変な意味じゃないヨ
Ah, I don't mean anything weird!
冗談でしゅた～!
Just kidding~!
どういうことだよ!
What is that?!
コミュニケーション能力欠けてるって!
Your communication skills are lacking!
ミオさんが僕より年下で若いからもしそういう事
Mio-san is younger and younger than me, so what if...
できない年齢だったらどうしよう
she's too young to do that kind of thing?
あ、そういう感じ?
Ah, is that so?
今いくつだっけ!?
What?!
でもおじさんは我慢なんてしないよ?
Uncle isn't holding back at all!
おー、ちょっと!
Whoa, hold on.
おじさんの何を知ってるんだよ!
What do you even know about uncles?!
最もブロックしたいおじさんを発表って思ったのはさ
The uncle I most wanted to block was...
マリンおじさん!
Marine-ojisan.
ふぶおじの方が気持ち悪かったと思うけどな
Mio-oji's message felt more disgusting, I think.
来週の土曜日空いてる? ちょっと怖くない?
Are you free next Saturday? Isn't that a little scary?
ちょっとちょっとどころじゃなーいっすね
"A little" is an understatement!
ふぶおじのはね、あの、なんでかっていうと、なんか最後にちゃんと誕生日おめでとう、お仕事がんばってねって言って、なんか普通の人っぽい感じで
Fubu-oji's had a normal-person vibe at the end, wishing happy birthday and asking about work.
いやいや、普通の人は「トロトロの若いエキス欲しい」なんて言わないっすよ!
"I want the youthful essence of young soft meat" is NOT what a normal person says!
「許してチョンマゲ」で許しちゃってんじゃん!
You forgave her with a "Forgive Chonmage"!
いやミオちゃん優しいな!
Mio-chan is so gentle.
ちょっとラプちゃん意味が…!
Wait, Rap-chan, what does that mean...?!
一生懸命考えたのに、なんでぇ～!
I thought so hard about it, whyyy~?!
早く見たいな、おじさんからのメッセージ!
I want to see it, an ojisan message!
あぁじゃあこれにしようかな?
Then I'll make one!
よっし、できちゃったの! おじさんできちゃった!
Done! Uncle is all done!
ラプちゃんに送っちゃおうかな?
Shall we send it to Rap-chan?
早く送れよ!いいからさ!
Just send it already!
じゃあラプちゃんに送るよ!
I'll send it to Rap-chan!
美味しそう🤤
Delicious-looking...
バブバブ!👶
Babu-babu!
ラプちゃん、気持ちいい!
Rap-chan, I feel good!
チョモランマって何?
Wait, what is "Chomolungma"?
隠語でしょが!!
It's innuendo!
直接の言葉を使っていいのかな!?
Can I use direct words instead?!
伏せてあげたんだよ!おじさんは!
I was covering for you, you know, as an uncle!
それは確かに。
That's true.
じゃあちょっとラプちゃんに送っちゃおっかなー!
Let's send Fubu-oji's message to Rap-chan!
じゃあいくよ!
Here we go!
ラプちゃん、突然だけど、イチャイチャしたいな～🤭
Rap-chan, out of nowhere, but I want to get touchy-feely~♪
モーレツ! おじさん号出航! ポッポー!!🚂
Severe! Uncle-go! Po-po-po!!
おじさん昔ヤンチャだったからね!!
Uncle used to be pretty wild, you know!
ホテルいっちゃう?! おじさん、いっちゃうよ✨
Hotel, let's go?! Uncle is going to go!
ちょっと解像度が高すぎる!
The resolution is way too high!
こんなふぶきさん見たくなかったんだ!
I didn't want to see Fubuki-san like this!
ふぶおじ本気すぎ!
Fubu-oji is way too into it!
じゃあ、おじさんいっちゃおかな!
Alright, time to send Mio-oji's message!
久しぶり!! 元気かな?!
Long time no see! You doing well?!
一生のお願い!!
The favor of a lifetime!!
ラプちゃん、パンツ何色?
Rap-chan, what color are your panties?
見せて欲しいの♪
Show me, please~♪
尿!尿やばい尿やばい。
Pee! Pee is coming!
変な意味じゃないんだけど…
I don't mean anything weird by it, but...
今度おじさん教えてあげるね✨
Next time, uncle will teach you.
やだ!やだ!いらない!
No! No! No!
おじさんのパンツの色はいいからいらっしゃい!
Uncle's panty color is fine, so go away!
そうなんなんじゃ、あがいわ…
That's right, so whose was the worst?
マリンさんから!
Marine-san!
ホントに気持ち悪い!
Really disgusting!
マリンさんのわ笑えない気持ち悪さ!
Marine-san's is an unlaughable level of disgusting!
ふぶきさんはちょっと面白かったから、
Fubuki-san was funny.
ちょっと次からLINEでもちょっと笑えるから。
so next time even with LINE it'll be funny.
ミオさんはなんかおじさんていうかさらのセクハラの男の人って感じじゃん?
Mio-san is just a harassing man.
おじさん見えなかったよおじさんっていうかさ、よくないよ!
Mio-oji wasn't an ojisan, it was just bad.
ということで、1週が終わりましたー!
And so, the week is over!
はい、終わりましたねー!
Yes, it's over!
いや、面白かったですね、こちら。
It was a lot of fun, wasn't it?
最も多くブロックされたおじさんは…
The ojisan who got blocked the most is...
マリンおじさんです!
Marine-ojisan!
あれ?!
Huh?!
お気に入りのふぶきちゃん連絡が取れないよ!
I can't even block my favorite Fubuki-chan!
最もおじさんになりきれなかったのは…
And the ojisan who couldn't pull it off the most is...
ラプラスおじさんです!
Laplus-ojisan!
なんでや!
Whyyy?!
ブロックされなかったってことは、
Wait, if I wasn't blocked, that means...
そんなに気持ち悪さが出てなかったってことだから良いことなんじゃない?
I didn't give off a creepy vibe, which means it's a good thing!
私なんか1番気持ち悪くなくて、1番気持ち悪いです!
I was the least creepy and therefore the most creepy!
おい!
Hey!
あなた負けてるんだからこれで終わりだと思っててもらったら困りますよ。
Hey, since you lost, don't think it ends with this!
ラプおじはですね、おじさんの力を養ってもらうために
Lap-oji, to help you nurture your ojisan powers,
渾身の親父ギャグを言ってもらいたいと思います!
we want you to say your heartfelt ojisan gag!
ちゃんとにおじさんになりきって!
You've fully become an ojisan!
おじさん力をね、前に出て〜!
Step forward with your ojisan power!
うるせえ!
Shut up!
じゃあちょっとふぶきさんここ立ってもらっていいですか?
Fubuki-san, could you stand at the front?
え、なんか必要なの? 必要です。
Huh? Is that really necessary?
あ、なんだなんだなんだ。じゃあいいですか?いいですよ。
Alright, good? Good?
行きますよ！ねえ、ろくちゃんの更新のおやじギャグまで
Let's go! And now, up to Rokuchan's updated old man gag,
3、2、1、どうぞ！
3, 2, 1, go!
フブキさ〜ん、ツルツルの体ですね。
Fubuki-san, what a smooth body you have.
このツルで縛っちゃおうかな？
Should I tie you up with vines?
ハハハッ
Hahaha!
はい、ということでね、今日の部活はここまでということです！はい！
So, that concludes today's club activities! Yes!
いやボドゲは楽しいね！
Board games are so fun!
いや楽しかったですね、ボドゲはね！楽しかったな～
That was really fun, board games!
ちょっと吾輩、ちょっと早退します。
I, Your Excellency, am leaving early.
あれ？
Huh?
あれ、ラプちゃん、ラプちゃん待って待って待って待って！終わってないから！
Hey, Lap-chan, wait, wait, wait! It's not over yet!
皆で帰ろう一緒に！
Let's all go home together!
うぇーん、皆で帰ろう一緒に
Waaah, let's all go home together...
一番慰められたくない人に慰められた……
Comforted by the last person I'd want to be comforted by...
ということで、またね、みんなでいつか部活動したいと思いますので、そのときもし呼んだときよろしくお願いします！
So, we hope to do club activities together again sometime, so if we invite you then, please join us!
お願いします！
Please do!
では部活動はここまで！ありがとうございました！
Well, that's all for club activities! Thank you very much!
バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
いやー、地獄のような企画でしたね、皆さん！
Man, what a hellish project that was, everyone!
いや、本当に、え、これを許してくださったホロライブ運営さん、そしてですね、え、おじさんギャグもやらせてくださった……
Seriously, um, Hololive management who permitted this, and also, um, who let us do old man jokes...
皆さま本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so very much!
さて、今回のね、生誕祭も皆さんもお時間見てください！なんと終わりそうな感じがもう48分！
Now, for this birthday stream, everyone look at the time! It's already at 48 minutes, feeling like it's about to end!
早いですねー！
That was fast!
あっという間でした！
In the blink of an eye!
面白かったですか？
Was it fun?
いや、もうボドゲをずっとやりたいなって思ってて、こうやってね、企画したところ……
Man, I've been wanting to play board games for a while, and when I planned this...
実はね、もう一本、企画でボドゲを取ってるんですけど、これはね、また後日公開しますので、そちらもお楽しみにしていただけれたら嬉しいです！
Actually, we recorded another board game project, which will be released at a later date, so I hope you look forward to that too!
結構いい時間なんですよ。そうそうそう。
It's quite a good time. That's right.
いやーね、面白かった、よかったです！
Man, it was fun, I'm glad!
またね、あの、白上部長のボドゲスコン部ね、ちょっと開けたらいいなと思ってます！
I hope to open up Fubuki-buchou's board game sukonbu club again sometime!
さて、今年の誕生日もそろそろ終わりを迎えますが、ここで重大な告知がふたつ！
Now, this year's birthday is coming to an end soon, and here are two major announcements!
ふたつ、ありまーす！
Two of them!
何かな？何かな？
What could it be? What could it be?
ではでは、まず1つ目は、こちら！ででーん！誕生日のグッズが販売されます！イエーイ！可愛い！めっっちゃ可愛い！
Well then, first is this! Tada! Birthday goods are going on sale! Yay! Cute! So, super cute!
ね、みんな、クロちゃんの、クロちゃんのね、グッズが欲しいて言ってたので、今回はね、あの衣装発表もありました、クロちゃんも一緒におるぜ！イエーイ！
You guys said you wanted Kuro-chan's goods, so this time, Kuro-chan, whose outfit was also announced, is here with us too! Yay!
さてじゃあね、まずはこちら見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's take a look at this first!
マフラータオル！イエーイ！こちらはYin先生描き下ろしの、こちらの一杯詰まりに詰ましまくってるマフラータオルでーす！
Muffler towel! Yay! This is a muffler towel packed to the brim, illustrated by Yin-sensei!
これね、色んなデザインがあったんですけども、なんか一杯ごちゃごちゃさせた方がぽいかなと思ったので、一杯敷き漬めてもらいました！
There were various designs for this, but I thought it'd be more fitting to have a lot of cluttered stuff, so I had them pack it full!
そして続いてはこちら！どーん！フブキとマスコットステッカー！まあ、最近ね、とあるイカのゲームでロッカーに色々貼ったりしてますけども、皆さんのねPCとか車とかバイクとか色々ステッカー貼りまくってください！スコン部もおりよ！そしてクロちゃんもね、なんと真ん中にどん！と澱まして、白上のね、お洋服の衣装も全部揃ってます！こちらのステッカーぜひぜひ貼ってください！
And next is this! Tada! Fubuki & Mascot Sticker! Well, lately in a certain squid game, people have been putting stickers on lockers, so please plaster your PCs, cars, bikes, and everything with stickers! Sukonbu is there too! And Kuro-chan is right in the middle, and all of Fubuki's outfits are complete! Please definitely put these stickers on!
そしてもう一つ！どーん！ネジマキツネTシャツ！イエーイ！こちら、ネジマキツネの下に、なんとホックスバーガーとしてね、白上の大好きなチーズのバーガーが、ありまーす！こちらサイズフリーサイズ、しかもめちゃめちゃでかいです！はい、めちゃめちゃ大きくてゆったりしておりますのでぜひよろしくお願いします！
And one more! Tada! Nejimaki Kitsune T-shirt! Yay! Underneath Nejimaki Kitsune, there's Fubuki's favorite cheese burger as a fox burger! This is free size, and moreover it's huge! Yes, it's very big and relaxed, so please check it out!
裏面にはですねネジマキツネね、これね、あの歩いてるのと倒れてるのと、あとねメカネジマキツネもいます。そしてなんか下に点線がありますね。これは一体何なんだ！こちら白上のね、あの手描きとなっておりますので是非ともよろしくお願いします！
On the back, there's Nejimaki Kitsune walking and fallen over, and also mechanical Nejimaki Kitsune. And there are dotted lines at the bottom. What could this possibly be? This is hand-drawn by Fubuki, so please look forward to it!
そして最後！これをもうみんなに早く見せたかったこちら！ついにできたぞみんな！お前らのぬいぐるみだ！スコンブぬいぐるみ！イエーイ！ついに、ついに手元にスコンブが！今回ねちょっとスカーフでのの、JPスコンブなんですけども、もしねあの海外に来た子たちは、スカーフのところリボンにねちょっと変更してもらうのもありですし、スカーフのままでもオッケー！イエーイ！ついにスコンブのぬいぐるみが出ますよ！嬉しい！
And finally! The one I wanted to show everyone quickly! Tada! Finally it's done everyone! It's your plushie! Sukonbu plushie! Yay! Finally, finally Sukonbu is in our hands! This time it's JP Sukonbu with a scarf, but if you're overseas, changing the scarf part to a ribbon is an option, and keeping the scarf is also fine! Yay! Sukonbu plushies are coming out! I'm so happy!
そしてそして更にさらに、どん！フルセットを買ってくれた方には、直筆サイン＆白髪押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがつきます！白上初のこのメッセージ付きのあのポストカードとなっておりますのでね、こちらよろしくお願いします！数量限定バージョンで直筆！そのほかはね白押しのメッセージとなっておりますので、こちらみんなゲットしてください！
And furthermore, tada! Those who buy the full set will get a postcard with a handwritten signature and silver-foiled replica message! Since this is Fubuki's first postcard with a message like this, please check it out! The limited quantity version has a handwritten one! The rest have silver-foiled messages, so everyone please get this!
楽しみにお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
この後10時から販売となりますので、
It will go on sale starting at 10:00 PM,
よろしくお願いします！
so please look forward to it!
きっと概要欄に載るかないURLがどうだろうか、
I wonder if the URL is in the description box?
そしてもう一個重大告知は、こちら！
And here is the major announcement!
Coming Soon!!
なんとこちら！
And here it is!
白神吹雪オリジナル楽曲がきたー！イエーイ！
Shirakami Fubuki's original song is coming! Yay!
楽曲ですね、あの西沢さんPさんことことさんに作っていただきまして、MVとYASUの春さんに作っていただきました本当にありがとうございます！
The song was written by Nishizawasan P and Yasu_tan. Thank you so much!
こちら本日24時に楽曲が配信開始です！
Today at 24:00, the song's release begins!
タイトル名は「コンコンビーツ」すごいね、ギターがいい感じチャカチャカしてる楽曲で、もうね周組の大好きな曲長になっておりますのでお楽しみに！
The title is "Konkon Beats"! It's a great song with catchy guitar riffs, so please look forward to it!
そしてさらに23時半からのアフタートーク内にて、MVの同時視聴を行います！
And furthermore, starting at 23:30, we will hold an MV simultaneous watch party!
こちらのマスター配信もよろしくですね、こちら23時半です。
Please look forward to that as well.
この配信が終わった後ですね、このお誕生日企画が終わった後なんかく地獄のプレミア公開の動画は皆さん予約されてるの気づきましたか？気づきましたか？
Have you all noticed that the premiere screening of the video is scheduled after this stream ends?
そのままですね見ていただければそのプレミア動画に飛びますのでよろしくお願いします！
Please go ahead and watch it as soon as it premieres!
こちら動画は普通に公開されるんですけども、公開された後のアーカイブがメンバー限定となります。メンバーシップ限定となりますので、
The video will be publicly available, but the archive after the public release will be exclusive to members.
便利ね、メンバー入ってないけど見たいという方は、
So if you aren't a member yet but want to watch it,
この後の配信そのままでダイレクトでね、ポーンと飛べると思いますので見てください！
you can jump straight to it after this stream, so please take a look!
よろしくお願いします本当的地獄となっておりまーす。
Thank you so much! It really is like hell.
さあ、どう地獄かっていうのはね、この後のこれを見ていただければわかるかなと。
Well, to find out why it's hell, you can understand by watching what comes next!
では最後となりますが、これを見て今回のおすこんだバラエティ終わりにしたいと思います！
So, this will be the end, but after watching this, we will conclude today's Sukonda Variety Show!
本当にお祝いありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much for the congratulations!
それではVTRどうぞー！
Now, VTR, please go ahead!
白上のフブキvsYAGOOの地獄のお笑い対決！
Shirakami Fubuki vs YAGOO: Hell's Comedy Battle!
イェーイ！
Yay!
やめろ！
Stop it!
やめるんだ！面白いことするの早めに！
Stop it! Do something funny quickly!
ということで今回はですね、白上がお笑いのけのなんとYAGOOさんとお笑い対決をしたいと思います！
So, today Shirakami will have a comedy battle against comedy genius YAGOO.
お笑いのけしん？初めて聞いた！
The comedy genius? I've never heard of that.
お笑いの、お笑いのけしん？皆さんご存知ですよね、もちろん。
The comedy genius? Do you all know about it, of course?
お笑いのけしんなんですか？
What is the comedy genius?
初めて知りました。
I'm hearing about it for the first time.
そうなんですか？
Is that so?
そうですよね？
Well, it's because of his smile, right?
笑顔だからごまかすと。
Because of his smile, he can gloss it over.
これもう余裕の、余裕の意味ですよ。
That's just a sign of his余裕 (composure).
YAGOOはいい感じのね、ナチュラルな笑顔ですね。
YAGOO has a really nice, natural smile right now.
なんか何も喋らないけどどうしたんですか？
He's not saying anything, what's wrong?
緊張するんですか、YAGOOさん。
Are you nervous, YAGOO?
今日ですね、お笑いのけしんYAGOOと一発ギャグでもモノボケでも
Today, Shirakami's comedy battle against YAGOO...
モノボケでも何をしてでもOKです。
can be anything, one-liners or prop comedy, it's all okay!
この後ろの審査員3名にのことは、笑わせ3人と笑わせられたらの勝ちということで。
If you can make all three judges in the back laugh, you win!
3人とも笑わせたら勝ち。
All three of them?
今日ねめちゃめちゃねあの3人のことを笑わせいただきますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
Today I'll definitely make all three of them laugh, so please look forward to it!
よろしくお願いします。
Looking forward to it.
笑いませんからね。
I won't laugh, you know.
怖いよ。
That's scary!
ちなみにYAGOOさん意気込みどうでしょうか？
So, YAGOO, what is your determination?
はい。関西人の意地をかけて頑張ります。
Well, I'll rely on my Kansai roots and do my best!
関西だ！今日初めて喋ったぞ！
He spoke in Kansai dialect today for the first time!
初めて喋ったぞ！
He spoke today for the first time!
本物だ！
It's real!
あのね、この3人を早く笑わしたほうが、ホロライブ1のお笑いマスターということで、
So, if you make those three laugh quickly, you'll be Hololive's number one comedy master!
絶対YAGOOさん負けませんから。
YAGOO definitely won't lose!
ホロライブ1か？
Hololive 1?
この3人笑わせてホロライブ1なのか？
Can YAGOO make these three laugh and become Hololive number one?
どうなんだろうな。
I wonder.
いやでも結構相席笑っちゃうからな、店長。
Well, but I often laugh easily, so managerー
相席、いやいやいや相席全然してください。
相席? No, no, no!
人生で1回も笑ったことないんで絶対笑いません。
I've never laughed once in my life, so I won't laugh.
なるほどね。
I see.
今日のはちょっとデカすぎるぞ。
Today's joke was a bit too big.
おかしいな、さっきすごい笑ってくれてたのに、ないときの時は。
Strange, you were laughing a lot earlier, but now you aren't.
おかしいな、もとということでやっていきましょう！
That's strange. Well, with that said, let's get started!
それでは3、2、1スタート！
Then, 3, 2, 1, start!
よし。Fubukiが面白い。
Fubuki's gag is funny.
じゃあもう、もうもはやこの時点でもう面白いから。
Well, even at this point, Fubuki's gag is already funny.
笑ってよ、その時点で笑ってくれ！
Then laugh at that moment!
なんだ？
What is that?
カメラ？
Camera?
来たの？
Did it come?
いいよ。
Here it comes.
お。
Oh.
いいよ。
Here it comes.
Fubukiちゃん、無理、無理ですか？
Fubuki, is that too much?
無理無理、なんかやってるぞ。
なんかやってるぞ。
She's doing something.
足、足なに？それ、何その足？
Her legs are... what is she doing with her legs?
笑っただろ、今笑っただろ！
You should be laughing by now!
なんだ、なんだ、なんだ、なんだ今の。
What on earth was that just now?
説明しろいわ！
Explain it, Fubuki!
あっ、何々？
Ah, what is it?
あっ、何？
What?
ホロライブのライブを見てる時のYAGOO。
YAGOO when watching a Hololive concert.
うん、ふふっ。
Yeah, yeah.
ちょっと遅い。
A little slow.
YAGOOさん、動き遅っ。
YAGOO's timing is a bit slow.
なんかYAGOOが凍ったみたいになってるんだけど。
YAGOO looks frozen like ice there, though.
笑ってくれてるじゃん！笑ってくれてるじゃん！
He's laughing, though! He's laughing!
笑ってくれてるじゃん！
He's laughing!
なんだ？
What's this?
100年後の…
100 years later...
YouTubeアイコン！
YouTube icon!
さっき凍ったやつじゃん、それ！
That was the frozen one just now!
また笑ってくれた！
He's laughing! He's laughing!
それ、ラップがやってたやつじゃろ、さっき！
That's the Rap that was playing earlier, you know!
めっちゃスタッフ何人もいる中でめちゃめちゃ滑ったやつじゃんそれ。
Even with staff and people around, that one was so frozen.
そうだ、そんな…ボソッ「1個だけ思いついたわ」とか言って。
He just came up with that on the spot, like "Ah."
ちゃんと3人に笑ってくれましたね！
He made three people laugh!
Did he?
今の…今のどうなんですか？笑って…笑ってた判定なんですか？
Wait, was he laughing just now?
笑ってたよ！
He was laughing!
嘘だぁ！
No way!
ズルじゃない、ズルじゃない！
There's no way that counts!
そんなの…ないのか？
That doesn't count!
ないです、そんな。
There's no way!
はいっ！
Yes!
やっぱ、面白いものはやっぱりね、皆さんに伝えていくべきだと思いましてですね。
Funny material is something we should share with everyone, you know.
YAGOOさんにはまだ無限のネタがありますからね。
YAGOO still has infinite material, after all.
いったんね、いったん3つお見せしましたけど。
Once, once, we showed three things.
ね、やっぱね、YAGOOさんがね、まずちょっとどの程度なのかちょっとね、今計りかねてるので。
Well, you know, YAGOO-san...
まあ、確かにね。
Well, true.
まあ、まあ、中笑いぐらいのネタをやらせていただきました。
So, I let him do about mid-laugh material.
めっちゃ笑ってたじゃん！
He made you laugh!
次はね、あのYAGOOさんにやって、お、見て、いただきますので。
Next, we'll have YAGOO-san do it, so look forward to it.
あの、ジュニア、大丈夫ですか？YAGOOさん。
Junior, are you okay, YAGOO-san?
もう、この絵面がズルいんだよ！
This visual is so sleazy!
さあ、行きましょう、皆さんね、ちょっと、表情、表情。
Let's go, let's go! Everyone's expression...
これでちょっとズルい。
This already looks sleazy.
ムッ、ムッ、ムッとした表情で。
Mute, mute, with a muted expression.
笑わせない、笑わせないつもりで。
I'm not trying to make you laugh, not intending to make you laugh.
はい、行きますよ。ということで、レーベル、YAGOOさんの挑戦、それと3人に、1、スタート！
Alright, let's go! Starting now, YAGOO's challenge, against those three, 3, 2, 1, start!
もたつきずるおじさん。
An old man hesitating.
おじさんじゃない！もうだっておじさんじゃもん！
That's not an old man! That's already an old man!
ただのおじさんじゃん！
That's an old man!
ゼロ、ゼロ、ゼロ！
Zero! Zero! Zero!
みんなまだ、大爆笑じゃない、大爆笑じゃん。
Everyone's still having a massive laugh attack.
はい、次、次。
Okay, next, next.
釣りするおじさん。
A fishing old man.
全部おじさんじゃん！
All of them are old men!
もうずれてる。
He's lagging behind.
やったね！
Yay, good!
よかったね！
Good job!
まだ、まだ、まだ、まだいける。
Wait, still more?
おじさん禁止、おじさん禁止！
Old man-san is prohibited.
なんやねん、おじさん禁止って。
What is an old man-san?
いや、おじさん禁止だと、かなり、しんどいっすよ。
Well, having an old man is pretty tough.
おじさん禁止だろ！
Old man is prohibited!
子供を応援するおじさん。
An old man cheering for kids.
おじさんじゃねぇか！
That's an old man!
頑張れ！
Do your best!
子供、子供。
Children, children.
なっちゃん、頑張れ！
Nacchan, do your best!
ファイアおじさん！
That's a fire old man!
ハンドおじさんじゃん、それ。
That's an on-fire old man!
そんなもんですね。
Can't be helped.
待って、ずっとマリンさんが顔を隠して笑ってた！
Wait, Marin-san was hiding her face and laughing the whole time!
涙が…おじさんが壺に入っちゃった！
Tears are coming out! The old man went into the pot!
おじさんシリーズ、ズルくないか？
Isn't the old man series too sleazy?
ズルかった！
It was sleazy!
ということで、今回のホロライブ一番のお笑いマスターは…
So, for this time's Hololive's number one funny master is...
YAGOOさんです！
YAGOO-san!
お前の中身反省しろわ！
Reflect on your inner self!
お前の得点高だろ！優勝して喜べ、おじさんでさ！
You got a huge laugh, be happy as an old man!
おじさんシリーズ！
Old man series!
ずっとおじさんじゃねぇか！
That's just old man again!
いや、みんなが笑ってくれてよかったよ。
Well, everyone laughed, so I'm glad.
カヴァーやん、カヴァー。
Cover! Cover!
いや、ちょっと、キングとして最後に、もう1つ…
Yeah, as the king, finally one more...
もう1つ、もう1つ！
One more, one more!
お願いしますよ！
Please!
次どんなおじさんが来るのかな？
What kind of old man is coming out next?
使ってない何かで、じゃあお代わり。
With one that hasn't been used yet, let's swap.
じゃあちょっと、お代わり行ってみましょうか。
Let's go for an encore!
お代わり？
Encore?
では、よーい、スタート！
Alright, ready, start!
鳩を育てるおじさん！
An old man raising pigeons!